<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
"file:////@docbook.base@/dtd/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title>@docbook.project.name@ User Guide</title>

    <pubdate>@build.date@</pubdate>

    <copyright>
      <year>Copyright @build.year@ easyb.org</year>
    </copyright>

    <releaseinfo>@docbook.project.version@</releaseinfo>

    <author>
      <surname>easyb Development Team</surname>

      <email><ulink
      url="mailto:easyb-users@googlegroups.com">easyb-users@googlegroups.com
      </ulink></email>
    </author>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>easyb is a behavior driven development framework for the Java
    platform. By using a Domain Specific Language, easyb aims to enable
    executable, yet readable documentation. </para>

    <section>
      <title>History</title>

      <para>Behavior driven development (or BDD) isn't anything new or
      revolutionary-- it's just an evolutionary offshoot of test driven
      development, in which the word test is replaced by the word should.
      Semantics aside, a lot of people have found that the concept of should
      is a much more natural development driver than the concept of testing.
      In fact, when you think in terms of behavior (i.e. shoulds) you'll find
      that writing specifications is easier to do first, which is the intent
      of test driven development in the first place.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Goals</title>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>test</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Appendix</title>

    <section>
      <title>Glossary<anchor id="glossary" /></title>

      <glosslist>
        <glossentry>
          <glossterm>BDD</glossterm>

          <glossdef>
            <para>See Behavior Driven Development</para>
          </glossdef>
        </glossentry>

        <glossentry>
          <glossterm>Behavior Driven Development</glossterm>

          <glossdef>
            <para> Agile software development technique that encourages
            collaboration between developers, QA and non-technical or business
            participants in a software project. It was originally conceived in
            2003 by Dan North [1] as a response to Test Driven Development,
            and has evolved over the last few years. The focus of BDD is the
            language and interactions used in the process of software
            development. Behavior-driven developers use their native language
            in combination with the ubiquitous language of Domain Driven
            Design to describe the purpose and benefit of their code. This
            allows the developers to focus on why the code should be created,
            rather than the technical details, and minimizes translation
            between the technical language in which the code is written and
            the domain language spoken by the business, users, stakeholders,
            project management etc. (Courtesy:
            http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Behavior_driven_development)</para>
          </glossdef>
        </glossentry>

        <glossentry>
          <glossterm>Story</glossterm>

          <glossdef>
            <para>Description of a requirement, which has an associated
            benefit and criteria for validation. Contains any of the following
            components: scenario, given, when then. It also may contain a
            narrative with the following components: narrative, as_a, i_want,
            so_that.</para>
          </glossdef>
        </glossentry>
      </glosslist>

      <para></para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>
